Okay, so I'm going to go through how I do an
efficient resolution
of, basically,
if we have a branch that is behind and has conflicts,
I'm going to do a little demo of how I do that.
You can do this in other ways, uhm,
I prefer this way, uhm,
so we're going to check out the main branch of Kumis Platform.
Now, I always run GitHub to make sure that everything is up to date,
so we have the latest main, you can do pull,
too, but GitHub is just easier. Uhm,
we have the latest main, and then I've already checked out Shiv's branch here,
which has, Thank you which is, uh,
is, as you can see here, uhm,
his branch is 30 commits,
31 commits ahead, and 3 commits behind of main.
Now, if I want to do a pull request, oops, if I want to
do a pull request with Shiv's branch,
you can say, you can see, cannot automatically merge,
right, because there's a conflict somewhere, so what do I do here?
Uhm, so, for me,
uh, the best way to do this,
and the cleanest way to do this, is to check out his branch locally,
uhm, and now every developer,
ideally, every developer should be doing this themselves on their own branches,
so, uhm, if we look here,
and we say, okay, we can get a little assessment,
uh, how far ahead, or like,
I'll do git branch here, how far ahead,
behind, is this branch versus
main, okay, so,
we can ask a little question here, but we already know it's,
you know, we already kind of know the answer,
but great, okay, it says 31 commits ahead,
3 commits behind main, now, we're if I do git rebase main,
I get a conflict, so,
now, I'm in a detached state, okay,
so, how do I resolve conflict, well, first of all, I could just abort,
git rebase abort, and now I'm where
I was before, but what I'll do here is I'll I will,
in Claude, say,
uhm,
New one.
Okay. Killed that, uh, Claude. Okay, so, uhm,
I'm gonna do the bang to say, to show the branches,
git branch, great. Now I'm gonna do the bang,
git rebase, main. It's gonna run to the same,
right, it's gonna start replaying the commits on top of main.
And, uh, it's gonna run and do the,
uhm, uh,
the conflict. Uhm,
can you help me resolve this rebase
and its conflicts? Ask me any questions
if you have, uh,
if, if,
there are unclear merge conflicts.
So we're just going to let Claude take care
of it. Uhm,
now.
So these are my two,
my, it says two behind or three behind.
So it played them. It's, this is where main is,
right? And then it started to play shifts,
commits on top of that.
So now what's our,
we, it looks like we have two conflicts.
So if you look at Claude,
Skills, Kumis,
Friend, Airlines,
Skill. Okay. So yeah, we'll see here.
We'll see here. We have, yeah,
a couple, a couple of conflicts. Now with what's interesting with this one is
that, um, we have,
uh, this, I changed my Claude.md and shift change hit.
So this is a real, a real actual, like, um,
if we look at Claude, um, we can look,
there are lots of diffs here.
So this would be a, a really nasty,
uh, uh,
even if you're doing a Gitmerge,
right? This would be a nasty one to do. You'd have to do them
individually. So, um,
uh, hopefully you'll ask me what should we do with Claude.md?
If not, maybe we'll figure it out.
Good.
So
it's looking at the conflicts. It's looking at what to do.
we're still in a detached state here.
I'll pause it until it's done. Okay.
It's still going, but I wanted to show this in the docs,
making rebates. It's easier. So if you do decide to do rebases,
which can be very easy, um,
make sure these are enabled in your Git config to
run these commands. So basically this re,
re, re command, very silly name, but what it does is it stash,
it saves resolutions with Git that
you've already created. So basically you don't have to always redo them
if you like abort a rebase and then restart a new one,
it'll know and use the previous one. Um,
then this autostash, basically,
yeah, this is if you have a diff,
it stashes before you start the rebase and unstashes at the end.
Okay.
So it's finished. Um, it had a ton of thinking on what to do
here. Um,
and so let's see,
I can see the whole picture. Here's my analysis. I mean,
which blah, blah, blah. Okay.
My resolution here. Keep, have, pads,
compact structure, so head in this case would
be, um, let's see, uh, the current rebased state,
or the current progress in the rebase.
So like, it could have commits that we haven't applied
yet. Um,
but it's somewhere in the middle of the rebase.
So, this is what it decided here, uh, so I don't know if I
like this, because it's, looks like it's removing a lot of what Shiv did
here. So,
I'm going to say, um, the, uh,
claw.md instructions
on shiv's branch.
Just interrupt
it really quickly. So, it's now, it should re- resolve these,
uh, conflicts with that in mind.
Okay,
so it understood that, uhm,
and now we have both files preserved with shiv's content.
Uhm,
now it's gonna, let's see what happened here.
Okay. No, no, no. Preserved
shiv's content,
added mine, resolved the commits,
or the merge complex.
Great. Oh, and it's done. So it did this skill as well.
So now if we look here, the rebase is done.
It's clean. Now, if we look,
uh, at our git log, we can see that we had
the three that I had my three commits off of main.
So it was three behind all of shiv's commits.
And now we have it cleanly rebased.
Okay. So, um,
now what we do,
and this is pretty important, git push.
If I just push, it'll reject it because it's now it's changed history,
right? That's what a rebase does.
So we're going to do a push force with lease.
This allows us to rewrite history,
but also allows us to recover it if we need to.
So it's a safe git push force. Push force, basically.
And now we're done. So I have,
if we go back to GitHub, um,
platform. So if we compare shiv's branch now,
which I've just pushed, always push to
able to merge. Perfect. Instead of here,
I'm going to do it here. And,
uh, actually here. I'm going to use my slash
PR command. Um,
I can say things like draft PR,
uh, or like, uh,
base branch release. I'll do,
I'll just do a normal PR slash PR command.
And what What this is going to do is it's going to look at
the difference between. All these commits difference between main and
shivs branch that we are,
that we now just resolve the conflicts on and
it's going to, uh, create a
nice PR for us. And this has worked,
this PR command has worked brilliantly for me,
actually. Um, I think it's a really good balance.
Of, of a mix,
it makes PRS that I would want to read basically.
Okay.
Force push, um,
it should, it
should, yeah. Everything up to date. I already pushed it. And now
if we go to pull requests,
Yeah,
see, so before I created the ER, since history was rewritten,
this needs a force push. Ah, it was going to use force.
Okay, good. Great, now we've got the PR.
We can open it. Beautiful.
So this is, no conflicts.
Uh.
Really good overview here. And we have all the commits and our history
is clean. We'll have co-pilot
review it, but, uh,
now I can merge this. Usually you would get someone
else to authorize it, but I know for this repo,
that it's fine. Um,
uh, I'm going to merge this into main and
we're done.